# SENIOR USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER IN PORTLAND, OR

# **Carlos Cuéllar**

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Senior User Experience (UX) Designer with 12+ years of experience crafting software solutions across diverse industries. Highly collaborative with stakeholders to transform business goals into compelling, technically feasible experiences that meet user needs. Extensive experience building teams, mentoring designers, and driving impactful design solutions in agile environments. Fluent in English and Spanish.

# **SKILLS**

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Design Tools: Figma, Sketch, Axure RP, Photoshop, Illustrator, Omnigraffle
- User Research: Dovetail, Maze, Miro
- Front-end Technologies: HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, Git
- Design Methodologies: Prototype Design, Interaction Design, User Research

### **SOFT SKILLS**

- Team Leadership
- Stakeholder Collaboration
- Agile Design Processes
- Cross-functional Communication

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# SENIOR UX DESIGNER, TRIMBLE; PORTLAND, OR 09/2021-PRESENT

- Led an international design team to create a modern suite of SaaS tools focused on accounting and finance solutions for the construction industry
- Successfully migrated 60,000+ users to new login system with less than 0.5% error rate by improving user flows and information architecture
- Conducted comprehensive user research, including:
  - Customer and stakeholder interviews
  - Contextual inquiries
  - Moderated usability tests
  - Competitive audits
  - Heuristic analysis
- Contributed to Trimble's Design System development, leading the team responsible for responsive design layouts and components to ensure consistency, accessibility and scalability across products

# SENIOR UX DESIGNER, GOLDSTAR EVENTS; PORTLAND, OR - 05/2015-09/2021

- Led the design of B2B solutions for ticket suppliers, enabling efficient management and promotion of inventory within the system
- Designed administrative tools for managing online events, optimizing workflows for partners and internal teams and reducing event posting time by 30%
- Created mobile-first solutions for consumers, including a redesigned seating chart UI to enhance the checkout experience that improved conversion by 10%
- Developed add-ons for partners, such as integrations with Eventbrite, to expand platform capabilities

## UX DESIGNER, LIGHTSPEED SYSTEMS; PORTLAND, OR - 07/2012-03/2015

- Designed cross-platform solutions for My Big Campus, a K-12 learning management system, supporting Android, iOS, Windows, and web applications
- Implemented semantic markup and scalable CSS to ensure web applications were efficient, maintainable, and accessible, resulting in a 40% faster load time
- Introduced and developed a live style guide adopted across multiple web products, promoting design consistency and streamlining collaboration with developers
- Collaborated on e-learning platforms and classroom management applications, enhancing usability for educators and students

# UX DESIGNER, HP AGRISYSTEMS; SAN LUIS OBISPO, CA - 11/2011-07/2012

- Created visual identity and interfaces for horsepower.com, an agricultural ecommerce startup
- Managed front-end development for digital platform

## **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

- Universitat Jaume I, Castelló, Spain Degree in Technical Engineering in Industrial Design, 2005
- Nielsen Norman Group UX Certificate Interaction Design, 2020
- Cooper U Interaction Design Training, 2014

# CONTACT

• Email: carlos@cuellar.fr

Phone: (661) 379-7273

• Portfolio: cuellar.fr/work

• LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/cuellarfr

Address: 711 NE 112th Ave, Vancouver WA 98684